字幕翻译：射手网www.shooter.cn
字幕微调+时间轴校正：EzDone Studio & MarcusZ
【极乐世界】
21世纪末期地球上疾病肆虐 污染严重，人口极大过剩
地球上最富有的居民，为了维持 他们的生活方式逃离了这个星球
麦克斯！
Max!
快过来！
Come here.
别让姐妹们等着。
Let's not make the sisters wait.
这是芙蕾。
Her name is Frey.
她也是新来的。
She's new here too.
你识字吗？
Can you read?
这是长颈鹿 是从非洲来的。
This is a giraffe. They lived in Africa.
你识字吗？
You can read?
是的。
Yes.
那里有很多机器仆人，从早到晚为你服务
There are many robot servers, and they serve you all day.
如果你住在那儿，你永远不会生病也不会变老。
If you live there, you'll never get sick, or old.
有一天我会带大家去那儿。
I'll take us there, one day.
- 真的吗？- 对，我保证。
- Really? - Yes, I promise.
芙蕾和麦克斯。
Frey and Max.
永远是朋友。
Forever.
麦克斯，你是不是又偷东西了？
Max, are you stealing again?
太让我伤心了，你干吗要这样？
It breaks my heart. Why do you do it?
为了存钱吗？
To save up ?
你想有一天买张票去那里？
You want to buy a ticket to go up there?
那里不是你能去的，我也是。
That place is not for you, or me.
可这不公平，嬷嬷。
It's not fair, sister.
我为什么不能去？
Why can't I go?
有时候我们没法理解。
There are things in life that can't be explained.
我们只能接受这一切。
We just have to accept them.
可我知道一件事。
But one thing I know for sure.
我知道你很特别。
You're a very special person.
有一天你会干一件大事。
One day you'll do something marvellous.
你就是为这而生的。
You were born for it.
我的小麦克斯。
My little Max.
（2154年洛杉矶 ）
你好啊，伙计！
Max, muy bueno!
去上班啊。每天早起去流水线上干活儿。
Off to work, huh? Gotta get up early, to work that line.
去让世界变得更好吗？
Wanna make the world a better place?
真是太好笑了，我得上班。太好笑了。
That's real funny, I have a job. Chistoso.
-得了，孩子！你觉得我有钱吗？
Por favor ninos! You think I got money?
我看起来像有钱人吗？
Do I look like I have money?
那你呢，你有钱吗？
How about you, you got a little money?
来吧，让我看看你有什么？
Come on, whatta you got in there?
等一下。
Wait a minute.
有五块钱，太好了，我有五块钱！我发财了。
Oh, it's 5 bucks. Hey, wait a minute. I got 5 bucks, I'm rich.
我终于能买张去极乐空间的船票了？
I can buy my ticket to Elysium, huh?
那是我的。
Alright.
请按次序排队 你们的车已经来了。
Please form an orderly queue. Your bus has arrived.
我没带东西。
I don't have anything.
检查过了，往前走。
Checked. Move on.
早上好，警官
Morning, Officer.
大量犯罪前科。多项重罪。包里是什么？
Extensive criminal history. Multiple felonies. What's in the bag?
基本上都是美发工具。
Hair products, mostly.
不，我逗你呢...
I'm just fucking with...
嘿...我是去上班，伙计。包里什么也没有。。。
Hey... I'm just going to work, man. There's nothing in the fucking bag.
行了，那是我的...
Come on, I...
轻罪，不服从指挥。
Misdemeanor: citizen disobedience.
我仅仅是去上班，伙计。
Just going to work, man. Come on.
通过。没东西，是吧？
- Checked. - Nothing in there, is it?
零容忍政策适用于所有公民。
Zero-tolerance policy applies to all citizens.
没闹心的事？
No shit?
你要立即报告你的假释官。
You must report immediately to your parole officer.
谢谢你，公民。
Thank you, Citizen.
不，谢谢你。
No, thank you.
（洛杉矶市医院）
芙蕾，二号床，骨折，谢谢。
Frey, fracture in bed 2.
麦克斯？
Max?
芙蕾...
Frey...
我还以为你在...
I thought you were...
- 什么时候回来的？ - 我回来有一阵儿了。
- When did you get back? - Been back for a while.
- 你好像没怎么变。 - 不，这次不是我的错。
- I see things haven't changed. - No, this wasn't even my fault.
当然不是。
Of course not.
- 让我看看。 - 怎么样？
- Let me have a look. - How is it?
骨折很严重。
Pretty bad break.
你真的当上护士了。
So you're a nurse, huh? You did it!
是啊。
Yeah.
真是太好了。
That's great.
你还在偷车吗？
You still stealing cars?
不，天哪。我早就不干那些傻事了。
No, God, I don't do any of that stupid shit anymore.
我在阿姆达因工作。做流水线，从底层干起...
I work at Armadyne. On the line, you know? Working...
- 芙蕾，三楼那边要你去。- 马上就去。
- Frey, they need you up on the 3rd floor. - Be right there.
- 现在既然你回来了... - 等一下。
- So, you know, now that you're back... - Just a second.
麦克斯，稍等。
Just a second.
多米尼加，你能照顾一下这里吗？
Dominica, can you take over here?
嘿，听着。既然现在你回来了。
Hey, listen. Now, you know, 'cause you're back and everything.
麦克斯，对不起。我得走了。
Max, I'm so sorry I have to go.
很高兴见到你。别惹麻烦了。
It's good to see you. Stay out of trouble.
我没有。
I do.
听着...
Look...
我明白，我知道你为什么离开那儿，我理解。
I know why you left the neighborhood, I understand.
如果我像你一样聪明，我也会闪人。
If I was as smart as you I would have left too.
一起吃晚饭吧。仅仅是...
Have dinner with me. Just...
要不喝咖啡也行。
I'll settle for a coffee.
- 不。- 天哪。
- No. - Aww.
我得再弄断条胳膊，才能引起你的注意吗？
Have I gotta break my other arm to get attention?
- 别这样。- ... 我真会这么做。
- Stop. - ...'cause I will do that.
我的生活很复杂，麦克斯。
My life is complicated, Max.
我只是，我...我很想你。
I just, I... I miss you.
- 我星期三晚上八点下班，行了吧？- 好的。
- My shift ends at 8 on Wednesday, OK? - Yeah, all right.
- 喝咖啡。- 喝咖啡，很好。
- Coffee. - Yeah, coffee. Right.
快走吧。
Get out of here.
所有假释犯必须通过武器核查
All parolees must have weapons inspection
你好。
Hello.
开始之前，我想解释一下。
Before we start, I'd just like to explain...
麦克斯·达·科斯塔，今天在34-B公共汽车站，违反了刑法第2219条。
Max da Costa, violation of Penal Code 2219. Today at bus stop 34-B.
是的，我就是想跟你说这件事。
Yes, that's exactly what I wanted to talk to you about.
这其实是个误会。
See I believe there's been a misunderstanding.
假释期延长八个月
Immediate extension of parole by a further 8 months.
等等，什么？不，不，我能解释是怎么回事。
Wait, What? No, no, I can explain what happened.
我开了个玩笑，然后，你知道的…
I just made a joke. And, you know...
不要再说了。
Stop talking.
警官记录了暴力和反社会行为。
Police officers noted violent and antisocial behavior.
很遗憾必须延长假释期。
We regrettably must extend parole.
检测到心率加快。
Elevation in heart rate detected.
- 要吃片药吗？ - 不用了！
- Would you like a pill? - No!
谢谢。我想解释一下...
Thank you, what I'd like to do is expl...
不要再说了。
Stop talking.
性格分析显示会有78.3%的几率回复到旧的行为模式。
Personality matrix suggests a 78.3% chance of regression to old behavior patterns.
偷窃高级车，用致命武器袭击，
Grand theft auto, assault with a deadly weapon,
拒捕。
resisting arrest.
- 你想和人类谈谈吗？ - 不，我没事。谢谢。
- Would you like to talk to a human? - No, I am OK. Thank you.
- 你的口气是在挖苦还是辱骂？ - 没有。
- Are you being sarcastic and/or abusive? - Negative.
辱骂假释官是一项重罪。
It is a federal offense to abuse a Parole Officer.
我知道。
Understood.
达·科斯塔！
Hey, da Costa!
- 你上班迟到了。 - 对，伙计，我碰到点小麻烦...
- You're late for your shift. - Yeah man, I had a little thing...
不，不，这样不能干活儿。你走吧。
No, no. You can't work with that. You're out.
不，不，我很好，伙计。我能干活儿。
No, no, I'm good, man. I can work.
这没什么，这个过会儿就能拆了。我没事儿。
It's coming off later today. I'm fine.
- 你没事？ - 我没事！
- You're good? - I'm good!
好吧，那扣你半天工资。
OK, I'm docking you half a day.
- 好的，行吧。 - 能干这活儿算你运气好。
- Yeah, alright. - You're lucky to have this job.
没有检测到武器，你可以进入。
No weapons detected. You are clear for entry.
请保持工作站的整洁
Please keep your workstation tidy.
整洁的工作站才是有效率的工作站。
A tidy workstation is an efficient workstation.
快看啊，伙计。他好像长得像你。
Hey check it out, man. I think he likes you.
他的脸做过换肤手术了。看上去不错。
Think he got his face peeled today? He looks good.
注意：所有工人必须完成每周的指标。
Attention: all workers must reach weekly quotas.
请向你的上级报告一切不安全行为。
Please report any unsafe activity to your supervisor.
如果我们找不到方法提升股价，
If we don't have a clear path to up-side,
我们的投资者会对我们失去信心的。
our investors are going to start losing a lot of confidence.
你觉得我跑到地球上来干什么？
What do you think I've been doing here, on Earth?
你以为我喜欢呼吸这儿的空气吗？
D'you think I enjoy breathing this air?
- 不，当然了，不过... - 我能做的都已经做了...
- No, of course, but... - I'm doing everything possible...
就是为了让公司恢复赢利。
to restore profitability to this company.
这公司还是我一手建立的。
The company that I built.
现在，我要失陪了，
Now, if you will excuse me,
我没法再和你们谈下去了。谢谢。
I have to not speak to you people any longer. Thank you.
34号关闭！
Closing 34!
34号点火。
Firing 34.
快给她做身份证！
Tag her, quick!
快快快，我们时间不多了。
Let's go, we don't have much time.
黑到三个异频雷达收发机密码。
We have 3 transporter codes, Spider.
好的，放到屏幕上。
OK, pull'em up on screen.
密码通过了。
Codes have been accepted.
启动飞船。
Fire up the shuttles!
我们要上去了！
We're going up!
- 欢迎光临。- 你好，夫人。
- Welcome. - Hello, ma'am.
- 去看看花园吧。 - 我们会的，谢谢。
- Take a look at the garden. - We will, thank you.
- 你好，德拉库夫人。 - 你好。
- Hello, Madame Delacourt. - Hello.
天哪，都长这么大了。
Hi, Ivan, how you've grown.
-嗨。最近好吗？
Hi. You alright?
- 挺好的。孩子们都来了？ - 对，和多米尼卡在一起。
- Fine. Are the kids here? - Yes, with Dominica.
我有份礼物要送给你。想看看吗？在沙龙里面。
I have a present for you. Wanna see? It's in the salon.
跟妈妈一起去拿吧。
Go get it with your mother.
- 在沙发边上。- 太好了。
- It's, by the canape. - OK
再见。
Bye.
夫人，要不要提提神？
Ma'am, would you care for a refreshment?
命令已经取消了。
Demand's cancelled.
（安全漏洞 飞船密码报失）
抱歉打扰您，夫人。我们发现有几艘无证飞船入境。
Sorry for disturbing you, ma'am. We have a number of undocumented ships inbound.
下午好，国防部长德拉库。
Good afternoon, Defense Secretary Delacourt.
（三级警报）三艘无证飞船正在靠近极乐空间领空。
3 undocumented ships are approaching Elysium airspace.
六号，七号紧急命令生效。
Emergency orders 6 and 7 are now in effect.
22/B39号协议正在运行。
Protocol 22/B39...
注意外来飞船。
Attention, incoming vessels.
你们未经许可擅自进入极乐空间领空。
You have made unauthorized entry into Elysium airspace.
- 爸爸。- 没事的！
- Dad! - It's OK!
立即回到地球，否则我们将采取行动
We will be forced to take immediate action.
你们违反了极乐空间的规定。
You are in violation of Elysium airspace.
普通警告没有用。
Standard warning didn't work.
距离我们一万五千公里，还在靠近...
15,000 kilometers and closing...
- 我们该怎么办，夫人？- 激活克鲁格。
- What do you want us to do, ma'am? - Activate Kruger.
夫人，根据355号行政命令，我们没有权力对地球使用我们的资产。
Ma'am, according to Executive Order 355 we are unauthorized to use our assets on earth
我正授权给你。
I am authorizing you.
是，夫人。
Yes, ma'am.
特工32A 数据包发给你了。
Agent 32--over. We are sending the packet--over.
（国民合作局）
欢迎 克鲁格特工。
Welcome, Agent Kruger!
他们距离我们一万公里，还在靠近。
10,000 kilometers and closing.
发送飞船坐标。
Sending coordinates to asset.
同步目标数据。
Three target data.
把它们打下来！
Shoot them down!
批准执行，21-B，批准执行。
Green light, 21-B. Green light.
导弹已发射！
Missiles away!
见鬼。
Shit.
侦测到导弹锁定，弹着预备。十...
Impacto inminente. 10...
八... 七... 六...
8... 7... 6...
五... 四... 三...
5... 4... 3...
二... 一...
2... 1...
击毁两艘飞船。共有四十六人伤亡。
Two ships destroyed. 46 total casualties.
导弹五秒后到达...
Impact in 5...
- 最后一枚导弹没打中。真可笑！
- Last missile was a miss. - Ridiculous!
只有一艘进去了。
Only one made it.
夫人，飞船已经冲进我们的大气层。
Ma'am, the ship has breached our atmosphere.
第一艘无证飞船着陆了。
First undocumented ship just touched down.
把里面走出来的所有人全都抓起来。
I want everyone coming out of that vehicle apprehendeded.
（公民 C·查维兹 女性）身份确认。
Identification confirmed.
扫描。
Scanning.
（检测到多重综合骨折）
启动重建程序。
Reconstruction process initiating.
不
No!
我们逮捕了三十二人，十三人死亡 还有两个非法移民在逃。
We have 32 arrests, 13 casualties, and 2 illegals at large, Ma'am.
身体重建完成。
Reconstruction complete.
你们因触犯68-C移民法案被逮捕！
You are under arrest, under the 68-C Immigration Act.
- 所有非法移民已被拘留，夫人。 - 好的。
- All illegals are now in custody, ma'am. - Yes.
送他们去驱逐部。
Send them to deportation, Get them off this habitat.
德拉库部长 请立即向帕特尔总统汇报。
Secretary Delacourt, please report to President Patel immediately.
德拉库部长，请向帕特尔总统汇报。
Secretary Delacourt, report to President Patel.
你好，伙计。 怎么了？
What up, man? ?qué te pasó?
跟平常一样，因为警察。
Lo es siempre, the police, man.
- 你没事吧？- 没事，不用担心。
- Are you OK? - Yeah, don't worry about it.
麦克斯，我跟你说件事。听着！
Max, I gotta talk to you. You know...
- 不 - 什么就“不”？
- No! - What do you mean no?
你都没听我说完呢。
You didn't even hear what I was gonna say.
- 行了，说吧。- 好的。
- Alright, go ahead. - OK.
你知道山上洛斯齐塔斯的房子吗？
You know the house of Doseta's up on the hill?
知道，他们有很多枪。
Yeah, the one with all the guns.
是的，他们有五辆车，都是新的。
Yeah, they have five cars. New ones.
我们三个去。明天午饭的时候。
It's gonna be three of us. Tomorrow, at lunch.
- 午饭的时候 - 就这计划？
- Lunch time? - That's the plan?
我的天哪 -你有更好的主意吗？
Jesus Christ.
- 你有更好的主意吗？- 对，我们带上一个人。
- You have a better plan? - Yeah, just take one guy.
太阳出来前就去。你们偷那两辆最快的车。
Go before the sun comes up. You take the two fastest cars.
把另几辆车的电池。
Torch the batteries on the other ones.
你耍我，去死吧！
Fuck you. Fuck you!
你上当了！
I got you, cojone!
求你了，伙计，你是最棒的。给我一年，就一年。
Oh please. You're the best. Give me one year.
- 我不想再回监狱了。- 就一年，求你了！
- I'm not going back to prison. - One year, please!
瞧瞧你自己，你以前是传奇人物，现在呢？
Look at you! You used to be a legend, and now what?
现在时间上午5点50分。
The time is 5:50 am.
没有检测到武器，你可以进入。
No weapons detected. You are clear for entry.
34号关门！
Closing 34!
（门故障）
注意，门没有对齐。工人将会...
Attention, doors are not aligned. Worker attend.
你拖慢进度了。
Hey, you're holding up the line.
不，我的机器卡住的！
No, no, I got a jam!
工人们每班使用洗手间不能超过一次...
Attention: workers may not use the restroom more than once per sh...
- 你干了什么？达·科斯塔？ - 没有，我只是让门重新启动。
- What've you done, da Costa? - No, I'm just trying to reset.
让我看看。
Let me look.
- 挤到栈板了。- 对，位置动了。
- The pallet's pinched. - Yeah, It didn't move.
- 你进去。 - 不，我是说...
- Just go in there. - No, I mean...
听着，要么你现在进去...
Look, you go in there right now...
要么我找其他人，然后你就卷铺盖走人。
or we'll find someone who will, and you can go clean out your locker.
- 别介，伙计。- 不，不，我没开玩笑，懂吗？
- Come on, man. - No, no. That's the deal, OK?
快进去！
In you go!
快点，伙计们！快回去工作！
Let's go, people, back to work!
见鬼。
Fuck.
不，不，不，停下！
No, no, no, stop!
嘿！
Hey!
（检测到器官组织）
嘿，快走开，危险！
Hey, come on, vamos!
太晚了！
Too late!
把他弄出来！
Extraction!
是他们先动手的，嬷嬷。
Sister, they beat me up.
我只是想住在那儿。
I only want to live there.
从我们这儿看那里很美是吗？
See how beautiful it looks to us down here?
是的。
Yes.
好，现在...
Well, now...
从那里看我们这儿也很美。
See how beautiful we look to them up there.
留着吧。
Keep this.
现在是你的了。
Now it belongs to you.
永远不要忘了你是从哪儿来的。
So you never forget where you come from.
出了什么事？
What happened?
你受到了致命剂量的辐射。
You have been exposed to a lethal dose of radiation.
你将会经历严重的器官衰竭。
You will experience catastrophic organ failure.
五天后你就会死。
In five days time, you will die.
出了什么事，你们为什么停工？
What is going on? Why has production stopped?
- 他被辐射了 - 别朝我呼气。
- He's been exposed ... - Don't breathe on me.
- 把嘴捂上。 - 对不起，先生。
- Cover your mouth. - I'm sorry, sir.
他的皮肤脱落或者什么吗？
Does his skin fall off, or something?
我可不想换床单，带他出去。
I don't want to replace the bedding in there. Just get him out.
- 是，先生。- 好，谢谢。
- Yes, sir. - Right, thank you.
卡莱尔先生，你的飞船准备出发了。
Mr. Carlyle, your shuttle is ready for departure.
请签名接受药物治疗。
Please sign this to receive medication.
米珀洛，超强效。
Miporol--extremely potent.
能在你死前让器官维持正常运作。
Will keep you functioning normally until your death.
每顿饭吃一粒。
Please take one pill with each meal.
感谢你的服务。
Thank you for your service.
昨天下午三点你击落两艘飞船，杀死了四十六个平民。
At 15:00 hours yesterday you shot down two shuttles, killing 46 civilians.
你处理非法移民应该尽可能低调。
Your mandate is to deal with illegals 'quietly'.
我已经意识到了。
I am aware of that.
另外你使用的这个。
And then there's the use of this... agent.
特工M·克鲁格先生。
A Mr. M. Kruger.
犯有十五次人权侵害。
15 human rights violations...
强奸，绑架，刑讯逼供。
Rapes, kidnappings, torture.
这个人已经被确诊有严重心理问题。
The man's been diagnosed with serious psychological issues.
我们已经明确告诉过你: 我们不再使用潜伏特工了。
We made it explicitly clear to you that we're no longer using sleeper agents.
跟我说说，帕特尔总统。
Tell me something, President Patel.
你有孩子吗？
Do you have children?
接受评估的是你不是我。
I'm not the one being reviewed here.
那我假设你没有。
Then I will assume you do not.
如果你有孩子。
Perhaps, if you did have children,
也许你会表现得更有益于...
then you would behave in a manner
延长我们这个地方的使用寿命。
that is more conducive to the longevity of this habitat.
我的想法和做法现在已经过时了。
I understand, it is not the fashion to think and to act as I do.
这我心里很清楚。
I understand that perfectly.
可是当他们来到你家。
But when they come for your house...
你为你的孩子建造的家。
or the house you built for your children,..
和你孩子的孩子。
and your children's children...
靠公关和竞选承诺是赶不走那些人的。
It won't be PR and campaign promises that keep them out.
只能靠我！
It will be me!
我听够了 这是最后警告。
I've heard enough! This is your final warning.
如果你再自作主张行动 你就会被解职。
Any further unauthorized actions, and you will be removed from office.
让我们永久性地开除克鲁格特工吧。
And let's discharge this agent Kruger permanently.
全都赞成？
All in favour?
很好，立即生效。
Good. Effective immediately.
（协议）
（内核更新 M·克鲁格特工，开除）
来点儿啤酒吗？
You want some beer?
你已经被国民合作局开除。
You have been discharged from CCB.
请去当地大使馆退还所有武器。
Please return all weapons to local embassy.
该死的政治！
Fuck your 'Politikster'! Fuck you!
伙计，等我一下。
Look...
麦克斯！
Max...
Max!
你怎么了
What's wrong? What happened?
天哪，我帮你。
Jesus, let me help you. Let's go.
麦克斯，怎么回事？
Max, what happened?
- 麦克斯，怎么回事？- 我不该到窑里去的。
- Max, what happened? - I shouldn't have gone in, man.
到哪里去？
Gone in where?
我受到致命剂量的辐射。
I took a full dose, man.
致命剂量。
A full dose.
你会好起来的，我来帮你。
You're gonna be OK. Let me help.
- 你会好起来的，麦克斯。 - 他们给了我米珀洛。
- You're gonna be OK, Max. - They gave me Miporol, man.
他们给了我该死的...米珀洛。
They gave me... Miporol.
我只能活五天了，我只能活五天。
I got five fucking days! I only got five days!
你得把药吃了。
You have to take this.
- 极乐空间能治这病。 - 我知道。
- They can fix this shit on Elysium, man. - I know.
- 我要去见斯柏德。 - 麦克斯，麦克斯！
- I'm gonna go see Spider. - Max, Max!
先吃药!
Take the pill!
给你水！
There you go!
见斯柏德,你需要钱.
To see Spider, you need money.
我把所有积蓄都给你 可也买不起一张票。
I'll give you everything I have, but it's not enough for a ticket.
他会给我一张票。
He's going to give me a ticket.
他会给我一张票的。
He's gonna give me a fucking ticket.
芙蕾，我们已经尽全力救你女儿了。
Frey, you know we've done everything we could to help your daughter.
今天我和委员会讨论过了，
But I had a meeting today with the board,
他们建议把你女儿送回家。
and they're recommending that we send her home with you.
她在家里我怎么在这儿工作？
How can I work here and leave her at home?
她随时可能发作，费萨尔医生。
You know it can happen any minute, Dr. Faizel.
我知道，如果她又发作了 你就把她带回来住院，这没问题。
I know, if she has another seizure, of course bring her back here.
但她现在不能住院。
But until then she's discharged.
这里不是极乐空间。我们没法治好她。
This isn't Elysium. We can't just heal her.
麦克斯！
Max!
好久不见啊，哥们。
It's been a while, my brother!
工厂那边怎么样啊
How's life at the factory?
- 我要请你帮个忙。- 什么，我没听见什么。
- I need to ask you a favour. - What? I can't hear you. What?
我要一张上去的票，和一个身份证。
I need a ticket. Up there. And an ID.
行，当然可以。
Yeah, sure sure.
位子要靠窗的还是靠过道的？
Absolutely. You prefer aisle or window?
我没跟你开玩笑。
I'm being fucking serious, man.
听着，我会回来的 我会回来为你干活儿。
Listen, I'm gonna come back and work for you.
你要什么都行，我一定会还你的。
Anything you need. I'll fucking pay it back.
知道吗？
You know what?
这个可是...
This... is...
无价的。
priceless.
这个是无价的。
This is priceless.
我问你个问题。
Yeah, let me ask you a question.
你知道每天有多少笨蛋，
Do you have any idea how many idiots
跑到这儿来，说跟你同样的话吗？
come in here saying the same kinda bullshit?
说什么我有个小孩，他们每天都来。
I got little kids coming here every day.
麦克斯，如果我是你， 我就立马离开这里，懂吗？
Max, if I were you, I'd get the fuck out of here, right now
麦克斯，别…
Max, No...
麦克斯，不要…
我为了你坐了三年牢。
I did 3 years for you.
就凭我为你 做的那些事，你就该送我上去。
Everything I did for you, you're gonna get me up there.
- 感觉到了吗？ - 来吧，杀了我。
- Can you feel this? - Go ahead and shoot.
现在我身体里都是放射物
I got so much radiation in my body right now,
要是溅出来还会辐射到你。
you're probably getting a little sick yourself.
- 你真的要死了吗？- 我要死了，混蛋 听见了吗？
- You really dying? - I'm fucking dying, motherfucker.
看见吗？结束了，把枪放下。
See this? It's over. I put the gun down.
把枪放下，把枪放下 都滚出去。
Put the gun down! Put the gun down! Get out of here!
听到吗？
OK!
听着，我在找人帮我做一件事。
Listen, I've been looking for someone to take a job for me.
可是我这里没人有那个胆量。
But no one here had the balls.
你说叫你干什么都行，对吗？
You said you'd do anything, right?
麦克斯。
Max...
- 没事吧？ - 我没事。
- OK. - I'm OK.
行了，在这儿 让我看看。
这个...
This...
我的朋友，
my friend,
这个就是你上去的票。
this can be your ticket up there.
你最后为我做件事，我就送你上去。
One last job for me, you earn your way up.
什么事？
What is it?
一个极乐世界的混蛋，懂吗？
Take an Elysian asshole, right?
一个亿万富翁，他下到地球上来做生意。
A billionaire who's down on Earth for some business...
他来…他来…管他来干什么，我们绑架他。
He's, he's here for, whatever. We hijack him.
- 得了 - 放松。
- Fuck that! - Relax.
我的计划比你想的复杂。
The guy's like much worse.
我们不要他的表 不要他的车 这些东西都不要。
Forget his watch, forget his ride, forget all that shit.
这个，我们要这个。
This, is what you take.
我们要他脑袋里的那些有机信息。
Organic Information, right out of his head.
我说的是银行代码、密码、登陆数据。
I'm talking about bank codes, passwords, login data...
靠这些能拿几亿的钱。
Access to billions.
你要做的就是接通他的大脑，用这东西把数据下载到你的脑子里。
All you have to do is plug into his brain, download the data to yours with this baby,
然后带回来给我。
and bring it to me.
这太疯狂了，麦克斯，算了。
This is crazy, Max.
我们一旦核实了数据 我就给你一张免费的单程票。
Once we verify the data, I'll give you a one way ride, all expenses paid.
还附送饮料和小吃。
Even throw in some snacks and a drink.
到时候你只要走进一间屋子，运行医疗机，你就痊愈了。
All you have to do is walk into a house and use the med-bay, and you're cured.
桑德罗会负责手术 你认识他吗？
Sandro will do the surgery. You know him?
怎么回事，我的天哪！
- Fuck... - Christ!
我没事。
I'm good.
事实上你看上去虚弱。
Actually, you seem all weak.
虚弱得一塌糊涂，所以...
And fucked up, so...
知道吗，我会让他们...
You know what? I have...
这太疯狂了 我们走吧，听我的。
This is crazy, let's get out of here, Please, listen to me.
我还能怎么办？
What the fuck am I gonna do?
我会让他们给你装上这个。
I'll have them install...
...这是！
...this!
第三代外骨盔甲。
A third generation Axo-suit.
它会和神经系统连接 让你和机器人一样强。
We hook this into your nerval system, and it'll make you as strong as a droid.
准备好做手术了，对吗？
You're already under the knife, right?
我们快走吧，求你了。
Let's get out of here, please.
我要一个四人团队，人我来选。
I want a 4 man team. But I pick them.
我会派我自己的数据师去。
I'm sending my own data wrangler.
脑对脑数据传输很难操作 -好的
Brain to brain, that is real tough.
不过我要带上胡里奥，你也要给他一张上去的票。
OK, but I'm taking Julio. He gets a ticket up there, same as me.
好，没问题
Yeah, sure.
好了，我去叫他们过来。
OK, I'll go get the boys ready.
等等！
Wait!
目标得是强·卡莱尔。
It's gotta be John Carlyle.
你说的是阿姆达因公司的执行总裁？
The CEO of Armadyne, Carlyle?
对，就是他。
That's the mark.
德拉库部长，卡莱尔先生来了。
Secretary Delacourt, Mr. Carlyle has arrived.
你来这儿是想。
You are here to persuade me to renew our Armadyne contracts, yes?
说服我跟你续签。
和阿姆达因公司的合作合同吧？
你总是这么聪明。
Astute as always.
跟我来。
Come with me.
我对你那些小想法不感兴趣。
I'm not interested in your little ideas.
我感兴趣的是更大的东西。
I am interested in something much larger.
这个地方在死去。
This habitat is dying.
它的内部得了一种政治病，这颗肿瘤必须被铲除掉。
There is a political sickness inside of it. A tumor that needs to be removed.
你和你的公司，你们的赢利越来越少。
You and your company are in need of revenue that is drying up.
是。
So...
你造了这个圆环。
You built the Torus.
你能不能重置服务器 扶植一位新总统上台？
Can you override the servers and place a new president in power?
这是政变吗？
A coup?
你的意思是要政变？
Are you suggesting a coup?
有可能吗？
Is it possible?
我可以写个重启序列？
I could write a reboot sequence.
关掉整个系统到那个时候？
It'd shut down the entire system, and at that point...
你就能编码一位新总统了？
you can encode a new President, yes.
这就是你要做的事？
Then that is what you will do.
如果成功，你们公司的合同就能续签两百年。
And you will have your contract secured for the next 200 years.
导弹防御系统，机器人一切用来保护我们自由的东西。
Missile Defense Batteries, Droids, everything we need, to protect our liberty.
你们的新总统 会保证这一切的。
all guaranteed, of course, by your new President.
你有活儿干了，卡莱尔先生。
Go! Get to work, Mr. Carlyle.
就是这个人。
This is the guy.
- 就是他吗？ - 就是他。
- He's the guy? - This is him.
坐下。
Sit down.
我们会切开你的头。
We're gonna cut you up good, homie.
温柔点，桑德罗，温柔点。
Play nice, amigo. Play nice.
先给他弄个身份证。
Let's get him an ID first.
我们先给他弄个身份证。
Give the chief one of my identification codes.
-是这个吗？ -对，准备好。
Get that ready.
手抬起来。
Arm up.
我们只有这个。
Weonly have
你找到什么？
What did you find?
这会并入你的DNA。
And we'll merge it with the DNA. Now you fit in.
你会融入那里 就像你是生在那儿的。
Like you were born there.
该动真格的了。
Now it's time for the real fun.
好了，快过来
伙计。
Hey, man.
嘿。
Yo.
这会疼吗？
This gonna hurt?
对，小妞儿 会有点疼
Yeah bitch, it's gonna hurt.
不过也很爽。
It's gonna hurt good.
手术结束你就会变成贫民区的忍者了。
When we're done with you, you're gonna be a  ninja.
玛丽安娜，把骨锯拿下来。
Mariana!...
我什么也听不见 快把骨锯拿下来。
Bring down the bone saw!
你不会弄死我吧？
This ain't gonna kill me.
不会有事的，老兄。
You'll be airight. Not bad.
麦克斯。
Max.
我在这儿。
I'm here.
我们能成功。
We got this, man.
We got this?
是的！
Yeah!
嘿！
Hey!
他醒了！
He's awake!
你挺过来了？
Made it, huh?
真没想到！
Surprise!
你还能打手枪呢？
You can still jack off, alright?
情况怎么样？
How's everything going?
他现在很强了？
Ready to kick ass?
你对我做了什么？
What the fuck did you do to me?
给了你一条活路。
Gave you a way out.
（协议重启 编译）
（序列完成）
（是否要保护数据）
（是）
（选择A-瘫痪 选择B-致死）
（致死）
（人脑上传准备就绪）
见鬼。
Shit.
你好，搭档？
What's up, partner?
这套装备感觉怎么样？
How's that suit working out for you?
感觉棒极了！
That shit is tight!
给我看。
Show me.
给你。
Hold this.
这是什么，传家宝吗？
Is it a family heirloom?
等一下。
Wait for it.
这是空爆弹。
Air-bursting ammunition.
你选定目标。
Designate your enemy...
子弹会在目标周围爆炸 杀伤半径五米。
and any round you fire will explode around a 5 meter kill radius.
还有...
And...
这玩意儿还配了同步爆破弹
safe detonation rounds for this bad boy.
不错啊。
That'll work.
行动吧！
Move out!
先生...
Sir...
飞船准备好了
Your shuttle is ready.
（卡莱尔：我来了）
能听见吗？
Do you read me?
收到。
Yes.
计划是这样的。
Alright, here's the deal.
我们在工厂外面等他的飞船起飞。
We'll wait outside the factory until we see the shuttle leave.
你发一枚爆破弹上去。
One of you opens an explosive round in it,
然后赶到坠毁地点拿数据。
goes to the crash site and gets the data.
好的，明白 。（弹药编码）
OK, copy that.
（已填弹）
好了，开始行动吧 上吧！
Alright now, let's go! Let's play ball!
你紧张吗？
You nervous?
- 不！ - 不？
- No. - No?
我都吓得尿裤子了。
I'm shitting myself with fear.
- 我们不会死在这儿的 - 对。
- I'm not gonna fucking die. - No.
上，上，上！
Go, go, go!
（阿姆达因公司）
十五秒后将加速到超声速。
Acceleration to supersonic speed in 15 seconds.
快点，快点，快点。
Come on, come on, come on!
（引爆）
发动机严重损坏。
Critical engine failure.
一位极乐空间公民在地球遇到危险。
Ma'am, we have an Elysium citizen on Earth in danger.
马上显示资料...
Data coming up now...
公民身份确认 强·卡莱尔，N8321P...
Citizen identified. John Carlyle. N8321...
我看见你了，混蛋。
I see you, motherfucker!
我这儿出了点事。
I have a situation here.
克鲁格，能听到吗？
Kruger, do you read me?
德拉库小姐. 很高兴听到你的声音
Ah, Ms Delacourt. How lovely to hear your voice.
有个携带敏感大脑数据的公民在城外
There's a citizen carrying sensitive brain data out of the city right now.
-几个小偷想抢劫那些数据。
Some thieves are trying to hijack it.
什么数据?
What's in it?
这是机密。
That's classified.
你才不会叫一个刚被开除的特工去帮你找什么该死的机密数据呢。
You don't call a recently deactivated agent to retreive classified fucking information!
政府不知道这件事，对吗？
The government doesn't know about this, do they?
我想要什么都行，对吗？
I can ask for whatever I want, can't I?
请做好防撞击准备。
Please brace for impact
请保持冷静，你承受的损伤为零。
Please remain calm. You have sustained zero injuries.
真是个好消息啊。
Oh, that's a real comfort.
我有一个条件 我干这活儿: 你得帮我复职。
I've got one condition. I do this, I get re-instated.
好的。
Fine.
我帮你安排了你喜欢的特工。
I've recommissioned 2 of your preferred agents.
当然了，完全是保密的。他们马上就会赶到你那边。
Completely confidentially, of course. They should be at your position any second.
把任务资料发给我。
Send me the mission data.
走吧，伙计们，快出来！
Let's go, guys. Out of the cars!
机器人，那边有几辆某种型号的车，上面有一个...
Droids, there appears to be some type of wheeled vehicle, with one
有两个人。
Two occupants.
他们都带着武器，我要他们死。
They are armed and I'd like them dead.
机器人！
Droid!
枪卡壳了！
It's jammed!
身份确认：麦克斯·达·科斯塔，联邦假释号61492-8-557。
Identified, Max da Costa. Federal Parole number 61492-8-557.
（锁定目标）
枪卡壳了！
It's jammed, man!
好了！
Got it!
（正在填弹）
它在填弹！
He's reloading!
- 没事吧 -我们快走，我去开门. - 快走，我掩护你们。
- Guys! We got the bastard! - Go! I got you covered!
快，快，快！
Go, go, go!
别乱动。
Don't fucking move.
拿过来！
Bring it!
那边还有一个
There's another one!
去死吧，混蛋!
Die, motherfucker!
别打目标!
Don't hit the mark!
不！不！他中弹了！
No, no! He got hit!
公民受到心胸外伤.
Citizen has sustained a cardio-thoracic trauma.
血压正在下降.
Blood pressure is dropping.
伤口不在头上?
- It's not in the head! - Is he breathing?
他还有气儿吗？ 有，伤口在胸上。
- No, it's in the chest! - Well, fucking good, man.
那我们还能干活儿 帮我托住他的头。
Hold his head, hold his head.
把这个插到你身上 快点。
Let me see your brain.
来吧，宝贝儿，快点！
Come on, Come on!
- 好. - 有反应吗？
- Yes. - Is it working?
对，我们在同步。
Yeah, we're syncing.
你不知道 自己在做什么。
You have no idea what you're doing.
距离目标一分钟，长官。
One minute to target, sir.
行了，同步上了。来吧，宝贝儿 传吧（同步完成）
We're syncing. Come on, baby, here we go.
我说能行吧。
It's gonna work. We got it.
发生数据抢劫，他们正在下载。已经在传了。
It's a data heist, ma'am. They're downloading now.
伙计们，有人来了。
Guys, we've got incoming.
该死的！
Fuck me!
快点，伙计们 快点。
Come on, guys, hurry up.
那是雷文机，是军用飞机
That's a Raven. That's Military.
- 就快好了 百分之九十七了，九十八。 - 快点，他们来了。
- Alright we got this, 97...98! - Hurry up, they're coming.
- 马上就好。- 九十九！
- Almost there! - 99!
搞定，成功了！
In! Here we go!
见鬼，天哪。数据被破坏了！
Shit! Data must be corrupted!
搞什么东东？这什么意思？（军刀 大脑防御）
What the fuck? What does that mean?
什么？这是什么意思？
What? What does it mean?
等等，等一下。
Wait. Hold on.
我没法读数据, 是乱码，读不出。
I can't read the data. It's scrambled! I can't read the data.
什么？
What?
- 快点，伙计们，我们得走了。 - “乱码”是什么东东？
- Come on, guys! We gotta move! - What the fuck does 'scrambled' mean?
该死的！
Fuck this!
不，不，我们再运行一次。
No, No! Run it again! Run it another time!
- 放开我，伙计 我放弃了。 - 求你了，再运行一次。
- Get off me, man! I'm bailing! - Please. Run it again.
去你的！快点，我们离开这儿
Fuck you! Let's get out of here.
你要去哪儿，桑德罗
Where the fuck are you going, Sandro?
快离开这儿，该死的！
Let's get outta here! Goddamit!
快走，伙计。
C'mon man.
快离开那儿！
Get out of there! Let's go!
快走，我们快走！
We gotta go! Come on! Come on!
头儿，有个逃跑的。
Hey, boss, we got a runner.
开火！
Fire!
这才是我说的那码子事儿。
That's what I'm talking about!
见鬼！
Fuck, man!
目标朝南-西南方向移动。
Target moving south-southwest.
快点，麦克斯 它来了！
Move back! It's coming!
我们找到另一个。
We got another one.
好了！
Again!
这计划错了，彻底糟透了，伙计！
This is wrong! This is all wrong, man!
保持盘旋状态！
Going into holding pattern, sir!
我看你往哪儿跑？
Where do you think you're going?
来吧
见鬼！
Fuck!
该死的！
Motherfucker!
来吧！
Come on!
不！
No!
不，不
No, no!
不，起来！
No! Get up!
起来！
Get up!
不！
No!
一名袭击者步行逃走了，夫人。
We've got one assailant leaving on foot, ma'am.
他们有数据。重复：
They have the data. Repeat:
那些小偷抢了数据。
The thieves have the data.
不惜一切代价逮捕目标。不要毁坏他的大脑。
Apprehend the target at all costs. Do not damage his brain.
我们走！有一个跑了。
Let's go! We got a runner, boys!
公民死于失血过多导致的心搏停止。
The citizen has suffered catastrophic blood loss leading to cardiac arrest.
死亡时间十七点四十五分。
Time of death, 17:45.
出来，你躲哪儿去了？
Come on, where are you hiding?
那是什么？
What's that?
看上去像是一群猪，头儿。
Looks like a herd of pigs, boss.
该死的！找到他！
Fuck you, man! Find him!
送我们回坠机地点 看看他们留下什么？
Take us back to the crash site, to see what they left behind.
明白。
Roger, that.
谢谢。
Thanks.
头儿，你最好过来看看这个。
Hey boss, I think you better come look at this.
这是我们扫描到的罪犯。
This is a record of what we picked up
和卡莱尔之间传输资料的记录。
being transferred between Carlyle and the criminals.
（协议重启）
怪不得她那么着急。
That's why she wants it so badly.
那家伙的脑袋里有打开王国的钥匙。
He's got the keys to the kingdom in his fucking head!
我们要找到他。
Now we just need to find him.
我派姑娘们出去。
Gonna let the girls out.
搜寻网格3到11。
Searching grids 3 through 11.
我授权了全面封锁。
I'm authorising a Full Containment Order.
把洛杉矶定为禁飞区。
Issue a No Fly Zone for Los Angeles.
- 整个洛杉矶吗？ - 凶手还逍遥法外。
- All of Los Angeles? - The murderer's still out there.
逮捕到他之前，不许有任何人离开那座城。
Until we apprehend him, no one leaves the surface of that city.
（信号干扰）
搞什么？
What the f...?
麦克斯。
Max.
- 嗨，亲爱的 - 嗨。
- Hey, sweety! - Hey.
我们可以回家了。
We can go home.
我的病好了吗？
Am I better?
我去开车，好吗？
I'm gonna get the car, OK?
我马上就回来。
Be right back.
芙蕾...
Frey...
麦克斯！
Max!
我的天哪，你怎么了？
My God, what happened to you?
- 见鬼，我去叫医生。 - 不，不。
- Shit, I'm gonna get the medics. - No, no!
- 我不能进去。 - 麦克斯。
- I can't go in there. - Max!
- 我不能进去。- 麦克斯，听我说，你得看医生，明白吗？
- I can't go in... - Max, listen, you need a doctor, OK?
有人在找我 他们要杀我。
People are looking for me. They're gonna kill me.
- 我来这儿是找你的，我需要你帮忙。 - 麦克斯！
- I came here for you. I need your help. - Max!
接受治疗得走系统程序。
You've got to go through the system to get treatment.
求你救救我，我不想死。
Please help me. I don't wanna die.
麦克斯！
Max!
别睡着
Stay awake!
- 我想看看那个人。 - 妈妈会救他的，好吗？
- I wanna see the man. - Mama's gonna help him, OK?
你快睡觉。
Try and sleep.
别睡着！
Don't sleep!
你实在是太重了，麦克斯 帮帮我！
You're too heavy for me. Max, help me!
起来！
Come on!
麦克斯，你能行的！
Max, you can do it, come on!
别睡着。来翻个身！
No, wait. Let's turn you over!
麦克斯，麦克斯，等等
Max, Max, wait.
- 谢谢。 - 谁把你弄成这样的？
- Thank you. - Who did this to you?
我不知道。我...我工作时受伤了.
I don't know. I got- I got hurt at at work.
我只好去帮斯柏德干活儿，这样才能到上面去治病
I had to take a job from Spider to try to get up there and get healed.
可事情搞糟了。我麻烦大了。
It went bad, now I'm in trouble.
妈妈？
Mommy?
宝贝儿，过来！
Hey, sweety, come here!
这人是谁？
Who is that man?
他叫麦克斯。妈妈跟你一样大时就认识他了。
His name is Max. Mommy knew him when he was your age.
- 这是玛蒂尔达 - 嗨！
- It's Matilda. - Hi!
你去看动画片吧，好吗？
You can go watch cartoons, OK?
我一会儿就来。
I'll be right there.
我不知道你有... 对不起，我该走了。
I didn't know you had... I'm so sorry, I need to go.
- 等等，麦克斯 等等，你不能走。 - 我不该来的。我得离开了。
- Wait, Max, you can not leave. - I shouldn't have come here. I have to leave!
麦克斯，她快死了。她已经到了白血病晚期。
Max! She's dying. She's in the final stages of leukemia.
我说过我的生活很复杂。我需要你帮我。
I told you my life complicated. I need you to help me.
- 可我不知道该怎么做。 - 做什么？
- I've no idea how to do this. - How to do what?
- 带她去极乐空间。 - 我帮不了她，我…
- Get her to Elysium. - I can't help her. I...
如果可以我一定会的。
I would if I could.
那这个呢，假公民身份。如果你带她上去，
How about this? Fake citizenship. If you took her there,
- 能用这个帮她治病吗？ - 那样没用的。
- could you heal her with this? - It doesn't work that way.
这是我的编码 是跟我的DNA锁定的。
This is coded to me, it's locked to my DNA.
那些找我的人，他们是… 你不明白这些人是谁。
The people looking for me. They... You don't understand who these people are.
一旦他们找到我，会把我们全都杀了。
If they find me here, they will kill all of us.
我唯一能帮你的就是离开这里。我向你发誓。
The only thing I can do to help you is leave. I promise you.
- 她是我的一切。 - 对不起。
- She's all I have. - I'm sorry.
你身上绑着绷带
You have bandages.
对，我绑着绷带。
Yeah. I got bandages.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
我不希望你生病。你想听故事吗？
I don't want you to be sick. You wanna hear a story?
什么，不...
N.., ah...
很久以前有一只猫鼬住在丛林里。
There once was a meerkat who lived in the jungle.
它肚子很饿，可它太小了。
He was hungry and he was small.
非常小。
So small.
其他大的动物都有食物吃，因为它们能摘到水果。
And the other big animals had all the food, 'cause they could reach the fruits.
于是它去和一只河马交朋友。
So he made friends with a hippopotamus
行了，别说了！
OK, stop!
这只猫鼬结局很惨吧？
It doesn't end well for the meerkat.
不，不是这样的，因为它可以站在河马的背上。
Yes, it does 'cause he can stand on the hippopotamus' back
摘到所有它想要的水果。
to get all the fruits that he wants.
- 河马有什么好处呢？ - 河马想要一个朋友。
- What's in it for the hippo? - The hippo wants a friend.
对不起。
I'm sorry.
（可能目标身份确认）
（麦克斯·达·科斯塔）
头儿。
Hey, boss.
找到他了。
I think we got him.
马上着陆。
Yank this fucking cunt!
- 妈妈，出什么事了吗？ - 没事的，宝贝儿。
- Mommy, is everything OK? - It's OK, sweety.
安全！
Clear!
这是什么？
What is this?
下午好。
Good afternoon.
很抱歉突然闯进你家。这并不意味着...
Sorry to come bursting into your home. Didn't mean to...
我不是故意要吓到你的小女儿的。
traumatize your young daughter.
我和我的手下是来这儿找一位先生。
Me and the boys here are looking for a young gentleman...
他不久前就在这房子里。
who was in this very house a moment ago.
希望你能告诉我们他去哪儿了。
We're hoping you can tell us where he went.
不。
No.
我。
I...
- 我不知道他去哪儿了。 - 我不喜欢...
- I don't know where he is. - I don't believe in ...
在孩子面前实施暴力行为。
...committing violent acts in front of the kids.
所以我要请你闭上眼睛，亲爱的。
So I just need you to close your eyes, sweetheart.
- 没事的，宝贝儿。 - 我真的需要你告诉我。
- It's OK. - I really need you to tell me.
嘿？
Hey?
- 想起来了吗？ - 妈妈。
- You remember now? - Mommy!
闭上眼睛，把你该死的眼睛闭上。
Close your eyes, keep your fucking eyes closed.
让她闭上眼睛。
Keep her eyes closed.
求求你，我不知道他在哪儿。
Please, I don't know where he is.
他受伤了，我救了他 然后他走了
He was wounded, I helped him and he left.
求你了！
Please!
你瞧瞧，这年头都没人讲义气了。
D'you fucking hear that? No loyalty nowadays, hey?
那是什么？
What's this here?
- 你这儿开了个医院吗？ - 她生病了。
- This a hospital you're running here? - She's sick.
她生病了吗？让我看看她，行吗？
She's sick? Let me have a look at her... Alright!
- 别碰她。 - 看见吗？这是保护的本能。
- Don't touch her. - See that? Protective instinct, here!
我说了不要碰她！
I said don't touch her!
我只是想跟她说几句话。
I'm just trying to get a word with your child.
不要碰她。
Don't touch her!
- 带上她，来吧。 - 你要带我们去哪儿？
- Bring her. Come! - Where are you taking her?
- 我有你想要的东西。 - 别害怕，宝贝儿。
- Now I've got something you want. - Sweety, it's OK.
没事的，宝贝儿。
It's OK, darling. It's OK.
给我坐下！闭上嘴！
Sit down! Shut up!
站住！
Stop!
不，不，别杀他。把枪放下。让他过来！
No, no, don't shoot him! Put the gun down! Let him come!
- 你拿到了什么东西，对吗？ - 什么？
- You got something, didn't you? - What?
所以他们会封锁领空...为了什么？
That's why they shut down the sky... what is it?
银行电汇？军事情报？一定是什么重要的东西。
Wire transfers? Corporate intel? You gotta have something big in there!
没有，我什么也没弄到！
No. I fucking got nothing, man!
全都是乱码。胡里奥死了，你欠我个人情。我们快去上面吧。
It all got scrambled. Julio is dead. You owe me. Let's go fucking now!
去不了。他们干扰了飞行系统信号！
We can't! The flight system is jammed!
没有人能上得去！
Nobody is going up there.
- 什么时候能恢复？ - 我怎么知道？（信号干扰）
- Until when? - Till I don't fucking know.
- 我一定要到上面去! - 所有人都要到上面去.
- I gotta fucking get up there! - Everyone needs to get up there.
我的人在想办法
My guys are working on it.
看是不是能有机会上线。
See if they have a hope in hell of ever getting back online.
不过，现在呢...
But, for now...
让我先看看你脑袋里的东西。
Let's just take a look at that head of yours.
别碰我，伙计！
Get away from me, man!
看着我，如果他们封锁整个领空。
Look at me, if they shut down the whole fucking sky,
只是为了你脑袋里的东西...
for what's in your head...
那么让他们开放领空的钥匙可能也在那里面，对吗?
Maybe the key to opening it could be in there too, right?
来吧。
Come on.
好了。
Alright.
为了这个，他们追到天边也要抓到你。
They will hunt you to the edge of the world for this.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是极乐空间的重启程序
It's a reboot program for Elysium.
谁拥有了这个，就能改写极乐空间的整个系统。
Whoever has this, has the power to override their whole system.
开放边界...
Open the borders...
让所有人都成为极乐空间的公民。
Make everyone a citizen of Elysium.
这东西能救你的命。
This can save your life.
- 能救所有人。 - 我什么时候能走？
- We can save everyone. - When can I go?
我的人想黑进去关掉信号干扰，应该很快能搞定...
They're trying to hack through the signal jam, but soon...
- 别扯淡了，我们什么时候能走？ - 我不知道。
- Don't bullshit me, when can we go? - I dunno.
五天吧...一周？
Five days... a week?
见鬼去吧，我根本活不了五天。我只能活几个小时。
Fuck you, I don't have 5 days! I got hours.
我的人在努力。
My guys are working on it.
你总是在努力，但总是没办法送我上去。
You're always working on it, You can't get me up there.
我都不明白：你干吗要想办法送人上去？
I don't know why you try sending people up there,
他们只会被打死。
they just get fucking shot down.
可有了那个就不同了 情况不一样了。
Not with what's in your head! That's what I'm talking about!
我们能控制系统，我们能说了算。
We would control the system. We would be in charge!
我们能彻底改变这该死的历史了。
We can change the course of fucking history!
回到刚才说的。
Back up then.
我脑子里的东西对他们来说很重要，对吗？
What I have in my head, is worth a lot to them, right?
不要这样。
Don't do this.
如果它落到坏人手里，他们会把我们永远隔绝在外。
If that falls into the wrong hands, they could shut us out for good.
听着，伙计，我现在就要上去。
Listen, man, I'm going up there right now.
如果你能找到我，我也治好了病，我就把东西都给你。
If you can find me, and I'm healed, you can have all of this.
- 我不想死在这儿。 - 你这样不对，麦克斯 别这样。
- But I'm not fucking dying. - This is wrong, Max, don't do this.
别开枪，别开枪。
Don't shoot him! Don't shoot him!
没事的，没事的。
It's OK. It's OK.
我一直想找个老婆。
I always wanted a wife.
可就是一直没法安定下来，你知道的？诱惑太多了。
Just couldn't quite settle down, you know? Too much temptation.
可是你...
But you...
你让我想要安定下来。
You make me ready to settle down.
你真的让我想安定下来，宝贝儿。
You really make me want to settle down, baby.
- 该死的，长官。 - 什么？
- Holy shit, sir. - Eh?
你最好过来看看。
You better come take a look at this.
- 干吗？怎么回事？ - 看看这该死的橡树。
- What is it? - Check this fucking oak.
带我们下去。
Turn us around.
- 接着。 - 是的，长官。
-Take it. -Right, sir.
把门打开
Open the door.
别过来，你们得照我说的做。
Stop right there, and you're gonna do exactly what I say.
否则我把自己脑袋炸了，明白吗？
Or I'm gonna blow my fucking head off, you understand?
好的！
Yeah!
我脑袋里的东西都能给你。
You can have everything in my head!
只要你带我上去 给我用医疗机。
Just take me up there, and get me in a med-bay.
- 我掌握的东西很有价值。 - 我们能帮你治疗。
- What I have is very valuable. - We can fix you up.
给你用医疗机，这些问题都能解决。
Put you in a med-bay, Sort all this cock-up.
走吧！我们带你上去。
Let's go! We'll take you up there.
上面天气不错 空气又好又干净。你会喜欢那儿的。
Weather's nice, air's nice and clean. Likely you'll dig it.
- 别想动歪脑筋！ - 上来吧！
- Don't you fucking try anything! - Step aboard!
见见我的弟兄！来吧。
Come meet the boys, come on!
别害羞，他们不会伤害你的。
Don't be shy, they won't bite.
我来给你介绍。这位是德雷克，这是麦克斯。
Let me introduce you. This is Drakie. This is Max.
-你好，猛男？
What is news?
我们走
Let's fly!
是的，夫人。我们已经逮捕了目标。
Yes, ma'am, we apprehended the subject.
- 打开领空 我们要回家了。 - 我们十九分钟后见。
- Open the skies, we're coming up. - I'll expect you in 19 minutes.
- 取消禁飞区。 - 是，夫人。
- Cancel the No Fly Zone. - Yes, ma'am.
等等...
Hold it...
等一下。那是什么？...
Hold it. What is that? ...
网络恢复了吗？马塞罗，这是怎么回事？ 恢复了吗？
Are we back? Marcelo! What the fuck is that? Are we back?
我们连上线了，斯柏德。
We're back online, Spider.
芙蕾...
Frey...
对不起，我会搞定的。
I'm sorry. I'm gonna make this right.
- 我们找到他了。 - 好的，他在哪儿？
- We've got him. - Alright. Where is he?
他在离开地球...去极乐空间。
He's leaving Earth... Heading to Elysium.
曼纽尔，黎戈，带上武器。我们到上面去。
Manuel! Rico! Get weapons! Let's get up there.
EL234请求在22区着陆。
Echo leader 234, requesting landing in sector 22.
收到，EL234 批准你们进入。
Roger that Echo leader 234. You are clear for entry...
- 我看到你有G-1手雷。 - 行了，给我退后。
- I see you got the G-1 there. - Hey, back the fuck up!
- 要不然呢 - 我就引爆它。
- Or what? - I'll let it go.
你想怎么样？
What you gonna do? Huh?
我要你脑袋里的东西，孩子。杀死他！
I want what's in your head, boy. Kill him!
抓住他。
Grab him, Deck!
我们要怎么做，夫人？
What do you want us to do, ma'am?
我要国土安全局逮捕所有从里面走出来的人
I want everyone coming out of that vehicle apprehended by Homeland Security.
把安全许可级别在五级以下的人全部清出这栋楼
Evacuate everyone on the level five clearence out of the building, now.
我警告过你的。
I warned you of this.
刚才一艘没有牌照的飞船坠毁了，对这儿是潜在的威胁。
An unlicenced vehicle just crashed potentially threatening the Torus.
会发生这种事都是因为你的无能，带他出去。
All because of your inability to act. Evacuate him.
- 别碰我。 - 这属于战争行为。
- Get your hands off me. - This is an act of war.
这种情况下国民合作局由我来控制。
That puts the CCB under my control.
现在我要去工作了。
Now, if you'll let me do my job.
我肯定你要去参加一个筹款活动。
I'm sure you have a fund raiser to attend.
走吧，先生。
Let's go, sir.
麦克斯！
Max!
快帮我下来！麦克斯。
Take me out of here, Max!
我在想办法！
I'm trying!
空气质量达到中毒状态。
Air quality reaching toxic levels.
快帮我下来。
Get me out of here!
建议您立即离开这艘飞船。
It is recommended you exit the craft immediately.
快跑！
Run!
见鬼！
Fuck!
两个非法移民在第三区朝东北方去。
2 Illegals heading northeast in zone 3
你去抓那两个，我来对付这个混蛋。
You deal with those two. I'll handle this pussy.
欢迎参观这栋壮观的豪宅 它占地…
Welcome to the spectacular properties from your...
错误
Error
不，不要啊！
No!
未探测到公民。
No citizen detected.
求你了，她生病了，帮帮我们。她已经昏迷了。
Please she's sick, help us. She's gone into a coma.
求你了。
Please!
我们是不是该弄掉这些东西？
Shouldn't we remove this thing?
不行。我们得先弄到数据。
Can't, till we get all the data.
这和他的神经系统连在一起。
It's wired into him neurologically.
数据没有受损吧？
The data is intact, yes?
看上去是的。
Data looks intact.
警告
Warning
我们可以把数据取出来，不过他会死。
We can still pull this data out of him, which will kill him.
这无所谓。
Oh, it's fine.
你们下载数据，让系统恢复正常要多长时间？
How long before you can download and turn the system online?
不用很久，夫人。
Not long, Ma'am.
所有资料都保留在机密云里，禁止一切访问。
Keep everything in a restricted cloud. Lock down all access.
马上开始准备？
Starting prep right now.
把那两个弄走。
And get these two out of here.
明白。
Roger that.
科特，想去抓头儿的女人吗？
Kurt, you wanna go get the boss' chicks?
好的，伙计
Yeah, good.
（接近警告 一艘无证飞船正在靠近）
采取机动规避。
Give them the runaround.
让他们忙活忙活。
Keep them busy.
找到了！
Got him!
我们走！
Let's go!
行了，50艾字节。哥们，准备好了吗？
Alright. 50 exabytes, buddy. Are you ready?
你要从他身上拿什么？
What are you taking out of him?
你想对他干什么？
Hey! What're you doing to him?
他会怎么样？
What's gonna happen to him? Hey!
该起床了。
Rise and shine.
- 起来！ - 麦克斯！
- Get up! - Max.
麦克斯！麦克斯！麦克斯！
Max. Max. Max!
给我进去！
Get in there!
是的，头儿搞砸了，呃？
Yes. Boss got fucked up, eh?
吃了个该死的手雷，额！
Ate that fucking grenade, eh!
他的大脑没事。不过他醒过来一定会气疯的。
His brain is fine. But he's gonna be pissed when he wakes up.
还记得上次他在印度掉了条胳膊吗？
Remember what cock-up happened in India when he lost his hat?
（颅面复原）
（完成）
克鲁格。
Kruger.
头儿？
Boss?
我是克罗。
It's Crowe.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
行了，准备好了，再打次镇静剂。
All right, all set. Let's reach the data.
准备好注射器，你抓住这个。
I got the needle prepped. You wanna grab this?
抓住针头！抓住针头！抓住...
Grab the needle! Grab the needle! Grab the...
- 他们把姑娘们带哪儿去了？ - 去军械库了。
- Where did they take the girls? - The Armory.
那地方在哪儿？
Where the fuck is that?
在第三层。
Level three.
检测到致命放射性中毒。你需要立即接受治疗。
Lethal radiation poisoning detected. You require urgent medical attention.
你这个笨蛋!知道自己干了什么吗？
You idiot! Do you realize what you've done?
你在城郊撞毁了一艘无证飞船。
You crashed an unlicensed vehicle into a suburban area.
我给你的命令是秘密行动。
Your orders were to keep this covert.
你还记得这是什么意思吗？
Do you even remember what that means?
你是不是疯了？你现在已经没用了.
Have you completely lost your mind? You're useless to me.
如果政府意识到我们在做什么
If the administration realized what we're doing,
会以叛国罪把我们吊死。
they'd hang us both for treason.
看在上帝的份上，克鲁格！你在听我说话吗？
For God's sake, Kruger! Are you listening to me?
是的
Yes.
是的，夫人
Yes, ma'am.
我在听。
I'm listening.
很抱歉，我们的飞船坠毁弄坏了那些车辆和人家的草坪。
I'm sorry that we crashed the vehicle and ruined someone's lawn.
没人能以叛国罪吊死我们。
But nobody is gonna hang us for treason.
现在我们说了算
We do the hanging!
把手放在上面 用力压住
Put your hand on it, keep pressure on it.
你现在很难受了吧？
How tough you be now, eh?
好了，孩子们！极乐空间终于要有个称职的总统了。
Right boys, Elysium is about to get its first proper president.
她需要医疗
She needs some medical attention.
我本来想治好你女儿的。
I was gonna heal your daughter.
不过，现在我要确保她永远不会被治好。
But now, I'll make sure she's never healed.
德雷克，永远别信政治家说的话。
Drakie, don't trust any of those politicians!
把这栋楼清干净。
Clear out this whole building!
谢谢！头儿。
Thank you, boss.
我要找到那个小流氓。
I'm gonna find that little gangster.
拿到他脑袋里的东西。这里现在是我的了。
I'm gonna take what's in his head. This place is mine now.
你敢跑到我家里来玩儿。
You want to come to my fucking house and play?
那就玩儿吧！
Let's play!
我要干掉那个小混蛋
。
I'm going to annihilate that little motherfucker.
嘿！
Hey!
这是怎么回事？
What the hell was that?
所有国民合作局的人员，请从最近的出口离开，冷静地前往底层...
All members of CCB please go to the nearest exit and proceed calmly to...
快点！快走！
Go, go, go!
不。
No.
不用。
公民死亡
Citizen deceased
现在启动紧急系统。
Emergency systems are now online
请根据指示行动。
Please follow indicated procedures
斯柏德！
Spider!
你能听到吗？
Do you read me, Spider?
麦克斯，你在哪儿？
Max, where are you.
我脑袋里的东西,能让所有人成为这儿的公民，对吗？
The thing in my head, it can make everyone a citizen here, right?
对。
Yeah.
你知道怎么把它弄出来，对吗？
You know how to get it out, right?
对。
Yes.
你确定吗？
You're sure?
是的，我确定。
Yeah, I'm sure.
好，你仔细听我说。
OK, listen to me carefully.
已选择军械库
Armory selected.
好了。
Set.
帮我启动。
Turn me on.
好了。
OK.
克罗,把那两个处理掉。
Crowe, get rid of those two.
乐意效劳，头儿，乐意效劳。
My pleasure, boss. My pleasure.
你在哪儿？小子,你在哪儿？
Where are you, Pikey? Where are you?
你好啊，小妞？
How is it, girl?
玩玩吧。
Let's play.
- 来吧，我会很好，很温柔的，我保证。 - 不，求你了。
- Come on, I'll be nice. Gentle, I promise. - No. Please.
- 来吧。 - 离我远点！
- Come on. - Get off me!
- 你希望我伤害这个姑娘吗？ - 不！
- Want me to hurt the girl? - No.
那就给我过来。
Then come here.
见鬼！
Fuck!
她还活着吗？
She alive?
目前还活着。
For now.
待在我后面。
Stay behind me.
我带你们出去。
I'm gonna get you out of here.
我有个计划。
I have a plan.
你听到这声音吗？
D'you hear that sound?
这是我来找你的声音。
That's the sound of me coming for you.
我会找到你我会宰了你。
I'll find you! I'll hunt you down!
芙蕾，我们得分头行动。
Frey, we have to split up.
- 什么？ - 听着。
- What? - Listen.
你到地面上去，行吗？拿着这个。
You're gonna go to the surface, OK? Take this.
找个房子，给她用医疗机。
Find a house, get her to a med-bay.
- 不，没用的。 - 别停下，别停下...
- Max, it won't work. - Don't stop. Don't stop...
她没有身份证。没法用医疗机。
She doesn't have an ID. It doesn't work.
这次一定能行。我有办法搞定。
It will this time. I know how to fix it.
已选择地面 - 快去。
Surface selected - Go.
跟我一起走。
Come with me.
- 我一会儿就来。 - 不。
- I'm right behind you. - No.
我保证。
I promise.
有个妈妈带着女儿刚才进了那边的电梯。
OK, a mother and her daughter just went up in that elevator.
她们要到地面上去找医疗机。
They're going to the surface headed for a med-bay.
你派个人护送她们到那里。
Send one of your guys make sure they get there.
我就履行诺言。
And we have our deal.
直接去医疗机。
Right to a med-bay, man.
我们走。快走。
-Let's go. -Let's go.
- 快走，快点。- 过来这边！
- Go, go, go! - This way!
快点伙计
Hurry up, man.
...启动紧急封锁...
...emergency lock down...
快到了，快到了
Almost there. Almost there.
怎么啦？
What's that?
只不过是点皮肉伤。
It's just a ... bitch!
这样才像话嘛。
That's what I'm talking about.
侦测到火灾...
Fire has been detected...
把住门！把住门！
Hold the door! Hold the door!
...都已经关闭...
...have been shut down.
快快快，开了！快走
- Come on! Come on! - Go, go, go
我们快走
Let's go!
该死的门！快开。
Fuck. C'mon!
快！你先走，快点。
Go! You first. C'mon!
快起来！站起来！
Come on! Stand up!
快起来！快起来！快点！
Stand! Stand up! Come on!
快起来！
Stand up!
你这个臭杂种。
You little fucker.
我要把你该死的头拧下来。
I'm gonna take your fucking head off!
伙计，你现在一定要站起来。
Dude, you should definitely stand up now!
不！
No!
待在这儿！
Stay there.
见鬼！
Fuck!
- 你以为你能打败我吗？ - 加油！麦克斯！加油！
- You think you could get through me? - Come on, Max! Come on!
我才刚开始呢。
I'm just getting started.
起来。
Come on.
别这么快就放弃，起来，快点！
Don't give up now. Get up, come! Come on!
你不止这点本事，我知道的。
You want more than this? I know you.
你是不是有点头晕啊？
You look a little bit dizzy, eh?
我划伤你了吗？
Did I get you?
你在流血，你得去看医生。
Are you bleeding? You must get that looked at.
伙计
Hey, boy?
你想治好那个小女孩？
You wanna heal that little girl?
你得先过我这关。
You just need to come through me.
你小子还挺能耐的。
You got some fire in you, boy.
你差点打败我。
You almost had me.
我们同归于尽。
We die together, boy.
好了，我们快走。
Come on, man, let's go.
我们快去吧，快。
Let's go, man, let's do it. Come on!
准备好了？我们走吧！
Ready? Let's go.
别让门关上！
Get the guards, now!
行了。
Alright.
来干吧。
This'll do it.
快点。
Hurry.
（公民资格授权：人口：非法移民 人口：合法公民）
可以开始了 可以开始了。
OK, we're good, we're good.
可以开始了。
We're good.
什么？
What?
（下载对数据主机是致命的）
麦克斯？
Max.
没关系吗，我知道。
It's OK. I know.
这个是没法恢复的。
There's no coming back from this.
医疗机也治不好。
No med-bay can heal you.
行了，把键盘给我。
Alright, give it to me.
拿着。
Take it.
好！
OK.
你只要按那个按钮。
You just have to press that button.
芙蕾？
Frey?
麦克斯？麦克斯，你在哪儿？
Max? Max where are you?
我没法实现我的承诺了。
I'm gonna have to break my promise.
我到不了你那边了。
I can't make it back up there.
记得我们小时候我说的话吗？
You remember what I said when we were kids?
记得。
Yes.
有一天我会带大家去那儿。
I'll take us there one day.
- 真的吗？ - 是的，我保证。
- Really? - Yeah, I promise.
你不会相信我现在看到了什么？
You wouldn't believe what I'm looking at right now.
告诉玛蒂尔达，我很喜欢她讲的故事。
Tell Matilda I really liked her story.
我明白了为什么河马会这么做。
I figured out why the Hippo did it.
来吧。
Come on!
你先来，来啊。
You go first. Come on!
每个人都有自己的才能，麦克斯。
We all have something special, Max.
一件他们注定要做的事。
Something we're destined to do.
一件他们为之而生的事。
Something for which we were born.
（系统重启）
去死吧！
Fuck you!
放开我！
Let go of me!
（阿姆达因）
（内核更新）
（新公民 已增加）
快点，求你了。
Come on, please.
我的宝贝儿，我亲爱的。（公民 玛蒂尔达·圣提亚戈）
My baby. My dear.
（检测到急性淋巴细胞白血病）
（100%清除）
解除战备，警官。
Stand down, Officers.
逮捕他。
Arrest him.
我不能逮捕极乐空间的公民。
I can not arrest a citizen of Elysium.
什么？
What?
伙计，干得好。
Doing a great job.
猜猜极乐空间现在归谁了？
Guess who Elysium belongs to now?
（新公民需要医疗救助）
（计算中）
（派遣急救飞船去地球提供医疗服务）
从我们这儿看那里很美是吗？
See how beautiful it looks to us down here?
从那里看我们这儿也很美。
Now look how beautiful we look from up there.
现在是你的了。
Now it belongs to you.
永远不要忘了你是从哪儿来的。
So you'll never forget where you come from.
我的小麦克斯。
My little Max.